Stephen Kent

Backend Software Developer

- **♀** 2700 Dorr Ave, VA 22031, Fairfax (US)
- stevekcode@gmail.com
- (571) 295-6530
- n stevejkcode in linkedin html pdf

About

I'm a backend web developer with several years of experience developing, maintaining, and managing cloud native web applications. In addition to implementation I have been responsible for driving the full development lifecycle, from design through to deployment, maintenance and operations and I am comfortable handling the demands of modern software projects. In my spare time I'm usually playing guitar (badly) or learning French.

Experience

Capital One March 2016 - July 2022

Mid Backend Developer

Developed Cyber Security solutions to enable developers to build secure software early in the development lifecycle. Principle engineer and architect on a platform to orchestrate and automate static and open source scanners for teams across the enterprise while also improving reporting and finding quality.

- Led architecture and design efforts for critical software components
- Designed and implemented core REST APIs via Express.js
- Wrote unit tests in Mocha.is
- Reviewed and mentored the work of Junior developers
- Wrote AWS Lambda functions in JavaScript and Python
- Designed and implemented distributed work queue systems with AWS SQS as well as Bull.js (similar to Celery)
- Created disaster recovery plans and carried them out during internal exercises
- Designed data models and indexing strategies in MongoDB and DynamoDB
- Met with stake holders to gather requirements and report project status
- Led Agile ceremonies such as sprint planning and review when needed
- Co-authored US Patent No. 10,387,659 for the de-duplication of static source code security findings

CFPR

November 2014 - December 2015

Jr. Backend Developer

Built tools to facilitate consumer protections and regulatory oversight. Developed a linting tool to help improve data quality for regulator submissions via a rules engine with rules defined in a flexible JSON schema.

- Developed flexible software components in JavaScript
- Designed JSON schemas for defining linting rules
- Wrote unit tests in Mocha.is
- Developed REST APIs for querying against public data (Census, etc) via Express.js
- Wrote queries for MongoDB via Mongoose

FCC

March 2014 - November 2014

Jr. Backend Developer

Developed backend Python code for aggregating and displaying cellular internet performance testing results.

- Developed primary Python software components, including daily statistics aggregation
- Worked with stake holders to gather requirements and ensure the process was able to meet stringent regulations, especially regarding user privacy
- Designed and published maps using Tilemill
- Designed data models in Mongo for storing aggregate statistics
- Performed geospacial gueries in MongoDB for bucketing results

Certifications

AWS Solutions Architect Associate

March 2022

Issued by Amazon

Link

Education

University of Maryland

Bachelors

Computer Engineering

Skills

Mid

Backend Development		Database			REST API			Cloud							Devops			
Mid		Mid			Mid			Mid						Jr				
JavaScript NodeJS	Python	MongoDB	Dynamo	PostgreSQL	Express.js	Swagger	Flask	AWS	IAM	VPC	EC2	S3	SQS	Lambda	Jenkins	GitHub Actions	Terraform	

Project Management

Scrum Agile Jira Git GitHub Volunteer

DSA National Tech Committee

December 2022 - Present

Volunteer

https://tech.dsausa.org/

I joined the DSA NTC where I have been helping with the development of myDSA, a centralized authentication and registration solution which uses KeyCloak as an identity provider and allows users to update their registration and profile information as well as log in to various other DSA services from a single location.

For my main project, I designed and built a solution for SSO onboarding for other DSA development teams using Github Issues forms along with Github Actions to create, maintain, and execute Terraform code which can register user applications within Keycloak. I"ve also assisted development teams with the overall onboarding process, helping with the initial form, reviewing their form submissions, and helping integrate their app with SSO once they"ve been registered with Keycloak.

Projects

EasyVocab

July 2022 - August 2022

https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/203110167

EasyVocab is an Anki plugin I wrote to enable easy and automatic generation of flashcards for foreign language vocabulary study.

Users can input a list of words they would like to study and EasyVocab will use Google Translate to automatically generate beautiful flash cards. Google TTS is also utilized to create audio pronunciation for each word, and reverse cards which have English on the front and the user"s target language on the back can also be created to help develop a two way association the words in both languages.